Welcome to the final project of the Udacity Self-Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree program.
ようこそ これが Udacity 自動運転車エンジニア向け Nanodegree プログラムの最終プロジェクトです
The goal of this project is to enable Karla to
プロジェクトの目標は ウェイポイントナビゲーションを使用して
drive around our test track using waypoint navigation.
Karla がテストコースをドライブできるようにすることです
Karla will do this while avoiding obstacles and stopping at traffic lights.
Karla は障害物を避け 信号機では停車しながらこれを実行します
Waypoints are simply an ordered set of
ウェイポイントは 簡単に言うなら座標の順序集合です
coordinates that Karla uses to plan a path around the track.
Karla はこれを使ってコースをたどる経路を計画します
Each of these waypoints also has an associated target velocity.
こうしたウェイポイントは それぞれに目標速度が関連付けけられています
Karla's planning subsystem updates the target velocity for
Karla のプランニングサブシステムは 望ましい車両行動に基づいて
the waypoints ahead of the vehicle depending on the desired vehicle behavior.
車両の前方にあるウェイポイントに対して目標速度を更新します
Karla's control subsystem actuates the throttle, steering,
Karla のコントロールサブシステムは スロットル ステアリング それからブレーキを動かして
and break to successfully navigate the waypoints with the correct target velocity.
正しい目標速度でウェイポイントをナビゲートします
Over the course of the project,
プロジェクトの間に
you'll be implementing components of the perception,
認識 プランニング コントロールのサブシステム
planning, and control subsystems.
それぞれのコンポーネントを実装します
In the perception subsystem,
認識サブシステムでは
you'll implement traffic light detection and obstacle detection.
信号機検出と障害物検出を実装します
In the planning subsystem,
プランニングサブシステムでは
you'll implement a node called the waypoint updater.
ウェイポイントアップデーターというノードを実装します
This node sets the target velocity for
このノードは 進行方向にある信号機や障害物に基づいて
each waypoint based on the upcoming traffic lights and obstacles.
ウェイポイントごとの目標速度を設定します
For example, if you see a red traffic light on the horizon,
たとえば ホライズン上に赤信号が見えたら
you'll want to set decelerating velocities at the nodes leading up to that traffic light.
その信号機に到達するノードで減速するよう設定します
In the control subsystem,
コントロールサブシステムでは
you'll implement a drive by wire ROS node
ドライブバイワイヤーの ROS ノードを実装します
that takes target trajectory information is input,
これは 目標トラジェクトリーの情報入力が必要です
in sense, control commands to navigate the vehicle.
ある意味車両をナビゲートするコントロールコマンドとも言えます
We've provided a ROS framework for these nodes,
こうしたノードのための ROS のフレームワークと
as well as a version of the simulator that includes traffic lights and obstacles.
信号機や障害物も含めたシミュレーターのバージョンを用意しています
The Ross framework we've provided works with both the Udacity simulator and with Karla,
用意されている ROS フレームワークは Udacity シミュレーターと Karla の両方で動作するので
so you can develop your project on the simulator
車両でテストされる同じコードを 提出する前に
before submitting the same code to be tested on the vehicle.
シミュレーター上でプロジェクトを開発できます
Coming up, we'll go over each part of the project in more detail. Let's get started.
次は プロジェクトの各パートをもう少し詳しく見ていきましょうそれでは始めましょう